" The names of persons and organizations in this movie "
" have been partially changed . "
" Produced by Taka Ichise "
" Directed by Koji Shiraishi "
This video documentary is deemed too disturbing for public viewing .
These are books written by Masafumi Kobayashi , a journalist
who had been chronicling supernatural phenomenon since 1995 .
He gathered accounts of strange occurrences ...
in his pursuit of horrifying and unsolvable mysteries .
Once he 'd begun using video in his research
he was able to compile his research on to videotapes .
That bomb shelter ?
Yes . It 's in there .
I saw it over there .
It running in the woods very quickly
This is where you saw the ghost ...
Was it suicide ?
Yes . I saw him in the fender mirror .
This is where ...
a family of five was massacred .
In April 2004 ...
Kobayashi finished his latest ...
video documentary , " The Curse " .
This has to have some connection .
But soon after that ...
At night on April 12 , Kobayashi 's house burned down .
Later his wife , Keiko was found dead in the remains .
But Kobayashi wasn 't found . He was declared missing .
Masafumi Kobayashi had mysteriously vanished .
His video , " The Curse " ...
reveals a truth too astounding for us to imagine .
" I want the truth . "
" No matter how terrifying I want the truth . "
" Masafumi Kobayashi . "
" November 12 , 2002 , Koganei , Tokyo "
" Masafumi Kobayashi , reporter of the supernatural . "
The spooky voices you mentioned ... What kind of voices were they ?
It sounded like babies ' voices .
Babies ' voices ...
" Ryoko Okui , housewife "
When did it start ?
A couple of months ago .
The sound comes from over there .
Who lives next door ?
A woman in her 40s and her boy , aged between 6 and 9 .
There are two of them .
They moved in about half a year ago .
That was the only time that I saw the boy .
I haven 't seen him since .
I see the mother every now and then when she goes out .
But she doesn 't greet me .
I 'm a bit scared . I don 't want my girl involved , either .
Let 's go to the neighbor 's .
Let 's go in .
What a mess !
Hello ?
Anybody home ?
I happened to be in the neighborhood doing some research and ...
What kind of way is that to talk to me ?
How can you talk to me like that ?
May I have a few minutes of your time ...
How can you ?
My name 's Kobayashi and ...
Impossible .
Give me a break .
" The strange sound was recorded on video tape . "
Let 's begin .
Can you tell us what the sonic analysis revealed ?
Okay .
We have the spectrographic analysis of the sound .
It has a band of noise all the way through it .
But here , there 's a unique signal .
I 'll play it back for comparison .
" The unprocessed audio signal . "
This one 's noise-reduced .
" The processed audio signal . "
As you can hear it 's like some kind of animal sound .
I have enhanced the signal .
Listen carefully .
A cat meows sequentially but this sound isn 't like that .
What 's interesting about this sound is ...
that it doesn 't repeat like a cat 's meow , it ends with an inhale .
That 's the characteristic of a human baby voice .
On closer examination
it sounds like the voices of more than 5 babies .
Several days after your visit ...
they moved out of that house .
What ? They moved out ?
How about the strange voices ?
Do you still hear the baby voices ?
Not since they moved out .
So her name is Junko Ishii .
Come here , Miyajima !
Excuse us now .
They died 5 days later .
Mrs. Okui lost control of her car when she was driving .
The car went over the divider into the incoming traffic ...
" Footage from a TV variety program , aired on August 3 , 2003 "
Good evening , everybody !
Good evening .
Very good , everybody .
Let me introduce you to
Mr. Koichi Hirotsu , the psychic .
Thank you very much .
Can you tell us how the experiment proceeds ?
The first experiment deals with clairvoyance .
" Experiment 1 , Clairvoyance "
In each of these containers
there 's a piece of paper .
It has a drawing on it .
I want you to imagine what 's drawn .
" First question "
10 children with ESP abilities from all over Japan .
We 're about to witness their powers !
They all look kind of nervous .
Everybody , concentrate right here .
Try to envision the paper in the container .
You 'll get a vision in your head .
None of us know ...
what 's drawn on the paper .
One of them is starting to draw what she sees .
" One of them is starting to draw what she sees "
Can she really see it ?
Let 's open the container
and take a look at the paper .
What 's on the paper ?
The answer is a double circle .
But not just a double circle .
Each circle has two points
where the line is broken .
It 's a complicated shape .
Did anybody get it right ?
" Results "
You there ...
She got it right !
Kana Yano
can you show us what you drew ?
Take a good look , everybody .
It 's drawn with extreme accuracy .
Even the scale is accurate .
This is incredible !
Kana Yano ...
She gave correct answers to
all the questions up to 4 .
" Fifth question "
Will Kana give an correct answer to the fifth question , too ?
Kana 's already drawing something .
" Results "
Show us what you 've got , everybody .
The answer to the question looks like this .
It 's totally different .
" It means Star in Russian "
I guess this one was difficult .
Maybe she 's tired .
Next we 'll make water materialize in sealed bottles .
It 's called materialization .
It is done by telekinetically envisioning water in the bottle .
Let 's do it .
" Begin experiment "
This requires intense concentration .
And now ...
you 're about to witness a miracle performed by Kana !
Look , Kana 's getting some water !
Can you see it ?
At the bottom of the bottle ... water 's gathering out of nowhere !
Of course , there 's no false bottom on the bottle , nor the table .
It 's the same girl again .
What were you thinking
when you did this ?
I thought about water .
When the water materialized ...
did you feel something different ?
Were you hot or numb ?
I had a headache .
My , God !
What is this thing ?
Some kind of hair ?
Yes . I guess she materialized it together with the water .
What was it that mysteriously appeared in the bottle ?
Tests done on the water that Kana produced , have come in .
" Professor Takaaki Yuhara , DSc "
The major component is water .
We found animal plankton which suggests that
it 's fresh water from either a river or a lake .
The hair in the water is indeed that of an animal .
It could be human hair , but because there 's no medulla development ...
it could be from a newborn baby .
" August 27 , Fuchu , Tokyo "
" Kobayashi interviewed Kana 's parents . "
Hello .
Thanks for coming .
She 's been sleeping all day ?
Since after lunch .
" Kana Yano , the psychic who appeared on TV . "
She 's had a slight fever since those TV experiments .
She 's spent lots of time in bed , resting .
We took her to the doctor but he couldn 't find anything wrong .
We 're very concerned about her .
I thought the program was pushing the children too much ...
Too many experiments .
I wonder if she 's exhausted her powers on that one occasion ...
" Unused footage of a TV variety show taped on October 23 "
Hello , we 're the Ungirls .
We 're so popular that ants crawl up our legs in the park .
When I 'm a pall-bearer
I 'm so tall that I have to hold the coffin myself .
We 're the Ungirls .
We 're on our way to a shrine , a popular ghost-sighting spot .
It was deemed boring if it was just the two of us .
So we have the actress Marika Matsumoto here too .
Good evening . I 'm Marika Matsumoto .
I heard that you have a sixth sense .
That 's right .
Have you ever had any supernatural experiences ?
Yes . Ever since I was a child ...
For so long ?
Yes . I 've seen apparitions .
Are you okay , Marika ?
I don 't know ... The back of my neck 's tingling .
You feel tingly ?
I 'm scared ...
Maybe we shouldn 't go in there ?
But that 's what we are here for , so we 're going in .
Here we are !
You want to go in ?
It 's spooky ...
Guys ! I feel something over in that direction .
I feel something really strange ...
This way .
We 'd better stay here .
Let 's all go in together .
It feels very strange ...
But there 's nothing here .
Maybe it 's here ... Yes , it is .
Can you bring the camera over here ?
Only these trees are dead .
Everywhere else the trees are okay .
They 're okay there , too .
Only here , they 're dead .
Look at this tree . So lumpy .
Yuck ... It 's dripping with something sticky .
What 's this ? Is it oozing from the tree ?
No ! Don 't touch it !
I mean it . Stay back ...
Is it bad ?
Shit !
What 's wrong ?
I heard something ...
Did you hear that ?
Did I ? I heard nothing ...
Something ... It was a low voice , like a man 's .
A man 's voice ?
Was that you ?
I 've had enough of this .
There 's nothing over there .
Stop the camera ! Stop it !
" November 26 , a live talk show , A Night of True Horror Stories . "
Wasn 't that something special ?
It was incredible . I was blown away .
How do you feel now , Marika ?
I feel embarrassed .
So this footage was edited out ?
That 's right . The director arranged for me to have a copy .
In the footage , you said you could hear a man 's voice .
It was a very low voice .
It sounded like it was calling me .
Did you see me turn when I heard the voice ?
I remember nothing from that point on .
Nothing at all ?
No .
Tonight , we have a special guest who 'll examine Marika 's condition .
A person with psychic ability .
Let 's welcome our guest !
Let 's hear it for him !
Calm down , he 's our guest .
Our guest has arrived in an outfit that 's very different .
Can you see us up on the stage ? Come this way .
We want you to use your power and give us your impression of Marika .
Ladies and gentlemen , this is Mitsuo Hori .
A man with unique psychic powers .
He 's engaged in activities
to protect humans against ectoplasmic worms .
Look at the flier you were given at the door .
It 's difficult to follow his thoughts ...
Hey , let her go .
You are in big trouble !
Pigeons !
My , God ! The pigeons !
The pigeons !
Show him the door .
Watch out for the pigeons !
" Midoriyama TV Studio "
" Kobayashi met the director of the variety show . "
Are you Mr. Kobayashi ?
- I 'm Kobayashi . - I 'm Shimbashi .
When I gave the footage to Marika , I edited something out .
I didn 't want to spook her .
This is right before she screams and collapses .
There 's something I want you to see .
" Sugishobou Publishing "
Hello .
This is Miyajima , our cameraman .
Nice to meet you .
I 'm Marika Matsumoto . It 's my pleasure .
It 's on the right side of you on the video .
You can see it just briefly . I 'll pause the image for you .
Right after this .
It 's here .
Oh , God ...
I don 't know if it 's related ...
What is it , Ms. Matsumoto ?
Something 's been bothering me lately
Take a look at this .
The drawing ?
I don 't know what it is .
But I find myself drawing these images unconsciously .
When did you start drawing these patterns ?
I guess ...
After the video shoot at the shrine .
The shrine ...
Wait !
There are so many ... I can feel it !
Wait , wait ...
Can you see something ?
No , I can 't see anything but ...
There are so many of them !
I don 't know what they are ...
I 've had enough of this .
Do you see something ?
" December 4 "
The slight fever she had stopped some time ago ...
But instead , she 's beginning to act strangely recently ...
It 's strange .
She 's often talking to somebody when there 's nobody in the room .
Who is it that you talk to ...
that your mother isn 't able to see ?
I guess it 's too late for all of us .
What do you mean ?
We 'd better take it , too .
No !
What 's wrong ?
Kana ...
Kana , you 'd better lie down .
Excuse me ...
" Footage from a variety show aired on December 9 "
Now , Maria Takagi went to interview a psychic !
Let 's watch the interview .
This psychic man was really something .
- You saw him ? - I did .
- It 's on video ? - Yes !
Okay , let 's not watch it .
No ? It 's like ... duh !
What kind of reaction is that ?
Here 's the interview with The Super Psychic !
This is Maria Takagi .
Today , I 'm here to meet with the super psychic who lives around here .
I can 't wait to find his place .
Is it true that your next door neighbor is a super psychic ?
Super psychic ?
I think he 's a freaking psycho .
I saw him several times putting out the garbage ...
He 's a freaking psycho .
He can 't be cured .
So he 's a freaking psycho .
Is this it ?
" Strange messages on the garbage "
Hello ! Is the super psychic home ?
Are you the super psychic ?
Mitsuo Hori ...
I can do that .
I 'm psychic .
Could I interview you ?
Is it alright ?
I 'm coming inside .
Can you see this ? We 've got to show this !
The room 's covered entirely with aluminum foil !
Hundreds of fliers are stored in these boxes .
What 's written on these fliers ? I mean ...
What are they for ?
For years , I 've been receiving dangerous information ...
Dangerous messages ...
Space ...
What ?
- Space ! - Space !
With space ...
I can connect ...
I can see the future ...
Many bad , bad guys ...
Ectoplasmic worms ...
It says so here . " Ectoplasmic worms . "
The worms are all over , crawling , squirming ...
The super psychic 's expressing himself with body language .
Is that his expression for the ectoplasmic worms ?
" December 22 "
Was anything out of the ordinary around the time that Kana vanished ?
For about a week before she disappeared ...
there was a man who kept visiting her .
I had no idea what he was talking about .
He was wearing a hat covered with aluminum foil .
And also ...
he had a long coat covered with aluminum foil .
And for some reason , Kana told me ...
that the man was of no threat to her ...
On the day that Kana disappeared ...
We found this strange flier . It was placed face down .
It says , " Help . " I think this is Kana 's handwriting .
See what Kana drew on this ?
Has she always drawn this kind of pattern ?
" Kana 's parents said they 'd never seen anything like this before . "
" Help . "
" The worms are increasing . If we don 't deal with them ... "
Hello , is Mr. Hori home ?
Excuse me .
I 'm a journalist doing some research .
Can you help me with my research into the missing girl , Kana ?
Who are you ?
My name is Kobayashi .
I believe we met on the talkshow the other night .
What ?
Come in !
Oh , excuse me .
What 's with the aluminum on the walls ?
Why are you covered with it ?
It protects me from the tingling .
Because the ectoplasmic worms are near ...
What are these ectoplasmic worms ?
These horrible worms ...
they are everywhere .
They eat people and they multiply .
Eat people ?
Kana ...
She was eaten , too .
Kana ?
Mr. Hori .
You know something about her , don 't you ?
Where is Kana now ?
I lost track of where she is ...
Mr. Hori ! Let go of my bag !
Stop it at once !
Kana !
This flier ...
I picked it up at her house .
What do you know about her disappearance ?
Quiet !
Blue ...
A blue building ...
Blue ?
Galvanized iron sheets ...
What is it ?
Cars ...
A parking lot ?
Is he drawing a map ?
The worms are coming out ...
The worms ?
The worms are coming out .
A young man ...
A young man .
The worms took Kana away .
They took her away !
To that direction ?
Wait a second , Mr. Hori .
I have a map for you .
This is where we are .
That way !
I can 't read the map ...
Did he say that way ?
What 's Kagutaba ?
Kagu ... What did you say ?
Calm down , Mr. Hori !
Are you okay ?
Calm down !
Go away !
Excuse us !
Something weird happened to the video image ...
What do you mean , " weird " ?
" Kobayashi looked for Kana according to the map of Mitsuo Hori . "
Mr. Kobayashi , how about that apartment over there ?
There is a parking lot .
But they 're in different positions .
That 's a blue building .
But it has only two stories .
This isn 't it .
This is difficult .
Hello , this is Marika Matsumoto .
I have something I want to show you .
What is it ?
" December 26 , Meguro , Tokyo "
I wanted to show you these loops .
When I woke up yesterday morning , I found the yarn .
And the wool was tied into these complicated knots .
With many loops .
I don 't recall putting the yarn here before I went to bed .
I don 't remember tying the wool in knots , either .
Something must have happened while I was asleep .
I 'm scared to fall asleep now ...
I 'll leave the camera plugged in .
Turn it on when you go to bed .
Okay .
" Later that night "
And you never woke up until morning ?
No .
And you remember nothing after you fell asleep initially ?
No , I don 't .
These loops look just like the ones on the wool .
They do ...
Very similar ... The way they are tied ...
Maybe this is the same banging noise recorded on the video .
It may be .
A girl who works for the same agency lives upstairs .
Is that right ?
How long has it been like this ?
Lately ...
Uh-huh .
Sorry to bother you .
What 's up ?
Is this for TV ?
Have you been banging on the floor ?
What ? No , I haven 't .
Did you hear a banging sound ?
I 've been here all day , but I didn 't hear anything .
- Didn 't you ? - No .
I heard banging ...
late last night , too .
Really ? I didn 't hear that either .
Are you sure ?
Have you noticed anything out of the ordinary recently ?
Have you felt inexplicably sick ?
Anything like that ?
No , nothing strange has been happening in my life .
Sorry . Did we scare you ?
No , it 's okay .
" January 6 , 2004 , Nakano , Tokyo "
I didn 't know what this was before ...
But I think this is a telephone pole
3 stories . Even the number of windows matches .
It 's a bluish-colored building , too .
And the room indicated is ...
2nd from the right on the 3rd floor .
The one with garbage bags on the veranda .
Let 's go to the room .
A person named Osawa lives here .
Hello , is Mr. Osawa in ?
I can hear something inside .
Excuse me .
Do you know anything about Mr. Osawa who lives next door ?
He 's a man of about 25 .
I barely see him . He 's often talking to himself .
He was also making the banging sound a while ago .
Did you hear that noise ?
Have you ever seen the man with a girl of ...
about 10 years of age ?
No , I 've never seen him with a girl .
" January 7 "
The pigeons are only on Osawa 's veranda .
It 's strange .
Keep the camera on the room .
Definitely .
There he is .
" A few days later , Osawa vanished . "
There 's a strange sound on the tape of Marika in her room .
I 'll play it back .
Around here .
Did you hear that ?
" We had the tape analyzed . "
The original sound 's here . On the right it 's processed .
You can compare them .
The noise is reduced on this recording .
What 's Kagutaba ?
What do you think ?
It actually sounds like ...
the voice I heard at the shrine that night .
You mean the shrine you visited for the TV show ?
Yes .
It sounds just like that voice .
The voice on the tape seems to be saying , Kagutaba .
Kagutaba ?
Does the word Kagutaba mean anything to you ?
No , I don 't think so .
I 've never heard of it .
" Kobayashi started to look into the word Kagutaba . "
It 's this word , Kagutaba .
Yes , Kagutaba .
It 's far fetched , but you could speculate that it derives from
Kamitama , meaning god 's spirit .
I see . God 's spirit ...
Have you ever heard a foreign word
that sounds like Kagutaba ?
I can 't think of any .
Is this Doctor Shioya ?
I 'm trying to find out about a strange word .
The word is Kagutaba .
Kagutaba ?
Yes , that 's right .
Kagutaba ...
I think I saw it in some book or something .
It 's a pleasure to meet you , sir .
Let 's get down to business .
The book you mentioned on the phone .
Can I take a look at it ?
This is an ethnological document compiled by the Tokita county office
I found the word Kagutaba mentioned in this book .
There 's a town called Shikamimachi in Tokita county .
Right next to the town
there used to be a village called Shimokage village .
It 's now at the bottom of a dam .
Before the village 's demise the villagers had a strange custom .
It was called the demon ritual .
Demon ritual ?
It was performed to pacify the demon .
And according to the book ...
The demon was called Kagutaba .
Does that mean that Kagutaba is the name of a demon ?
Well , it 's difficult to say . I think that it was just ...
convenient for them to call the unknown entity a demon .
This is a document that is over 200 years old .
It says Kagutaba right here .
The kanji characters for " disaster , tool and spirit . "
The 3 characters make up the word Kagutaba .
A tool that 's capable of causing disasters .
That 's what it means .
A long time ago , in Shimokage village ...
there was a group of sorcerers who migrated from the west .
They developed a type of sorcery called " Shimokage 's Way . "
One of their spells was called the " Kagutaba method . "
The sorcerer performed the spell to summon Kagutaba ...
which was sent to an adversary to put him under a deadly spell .
The document says that that was the role of Kagutaba .
But in one incident , when a sorcerer summoned Kagutaba ...
it disobeyed the instructions of the sorcerer .
It started to do evil things on its own .
So the sorcerer ... performed another spell
and finally succeeded in confining Kagutaba deep underground .
" Shimokage Village submerged with the construction of Shikami Dam in 1978 "
" The demon ritual was discontinued . "
This is Shikami town hall .
I 'm interested in the old rituals performed
at Shimokage village before it went underwater .
Okay ... Hold on please .
So you want to know about the Shimokage rituals ?
Yes , I do .
We don 't have it very well documented so ...
I 'll introduce you to someone .
Mr. Tanimura researches local history .
Hello , my name 's Kobayashi .
Oh , hello there .
Please come in .
The ritual was never performed publicly .
So there 's no documentation .
But the last ritual performed in 1978 was filmed
by a film production contracted by Mr. Ishii , the priest .
These are the 16mm films .
I pleaded with the Ishii family to give them to me .
This is the video . I transferred the film to video .
Shimokage village was a community of sorcerers .
The villagers still believe in sorcery .
Now it 's becoming a fading memory
but they still place a sickle at the door to keep away evil spirits .
Those who left the village have a sickle above their front doors .
Interesting .
" We don 't need a dam ! "
Shimokage sorcerers used dogs in their rituals .
That 's why the villagers still have dogs .
This is the Demon Shrine where the ritual was performed .
Mr. Ishii was a priest at this shrine .
You 'll see him in a minute .
Look . That 's Kagutaba .
This ritual is to pacify the demon .
Now Kagutaba is rampaging .
That 's Ishii , the priest .
He is going to pacify Kagutaba .
Now the priest will bow ...
One bow , four claps ... and one bow .
This is a distinctive way to bow , only done at this shrine .
Usually it 's two bows , two claps and one bow .
But this is one bow , four claps , one bow .
There is no other place in Japan where people bow in this manner .
But after the priest bowed ...
The woman who was playing the part of Kagutaba became delirious .
They had to stop the ritual .
The religious villagers said that she was possessed .
Some said that owing to the dam plan ...
the ritual wouldn 't be performed again , which angered Kagutaba .
They thought it was some kind of curse .
In the legend , Kagutaba was confined underneath Shimokage village .
And it 's the demon in the ritual .
What was it really ?
Nobody knows for sure .
I would like to meet Mr. Ishii , the priest .
Is that possible ?
7 years ago , immediately after giving me the film ...
Mr. Ishii died from an illness .
So did his wife but their only daughter 's still alive .
She was the possessed woman in the film ...
She recently moved back here from Tokyo .
I heard that she lives with her son in the Ishii house .
She 's in the Mikaishi community ,
where the Shimokage villagers moved to .
Mikaishi ?
I also heard that she 's a bit eccentric .
I don 't know if she 'll talk to you .
" Mikaishi Village "
I think we 're almost there .
What 's this ?
This has to have some connection .
Hello ?
Anybody home ?
How can you talk to me like that ! ?
I 'm asking you ! How can you talk to me like that ?
Did you see her ?
I did .
A woman in her 40s and her boy , aged between 6 and 9 .
How can you just talk to me like that ?
So her name is Junko Ishii .
Kobayashi asked around .
Look , the sickle .
Hello , anybody home ?
Is anybody home ?
Nobody .
May I help you ?
Excuse me but do you know the Ishii house down the street ?
There seems to be something strange ...
Yeah , ever since the daughter came back .
You 'd best stay away from her .
For you own sake .
Excuse me .
What ?
Sorry to bother you .
TV ?
You know Mrs. Ishii down the street .
Ishii ?
I 'm a journalist doing research . You may be able to help me .
Could you help me ?
Come in .
Oh , thank you so much .
I was a good friend of Junko 's before she moved out .
She left the village to go to nursing school in Tokyo .
Do you remember the name of the school ?
Musashino Nurse School or something . I don 't remember clearly .
How can I put this ... Has Junko always been ...
mentally disturbed like she is now ?
Not at all .
She was just a friendly , regular girl .
Was she ?
She changed after the demon ritual .
The demon ritual ?
She started to act strangely .
I think the ritual caused her to become possessed .
She told me that she 'd heard god 's voice .
She said she had to obey his words .
She became kind of strange after that .
I heard that people thought it was the Kagutaba 's curse .
Do you think she was ...
Excuse me ?
Hello ?
" January 21 , Musashino , Tokyo "
May I ask a few questions about Junko Ishii , one of your graduates ?
After she graduated in 1982
she got a job at an obstetric clinic in Hachioji .
I can disclose the name of the clinic
but it closed in 2000 .
May I ask you some questions
regarding somebody you used to work with ?
Sure .
Junko Ishii . What kind of a person was she ?
She was a very hardworking woman .
Quiet in a spooky sort of way .
She was the kind of woman who only talks about work .
The clinic we used to work for ...
performed abortions even into the 22nd week of pregnancies .
It 's clearly illegal .
And she was the one in charge of disposing of the aborted embryos .
There was a rumor that she took the embryos home .
" Did she really take the embryos ? "
" If she did , for what purpose ? "
" February 6 "
Midori ? Is she your colleague ...
the one who lives directly upstairs ?
Yes . Midori has ...
She 's dead .
The police came and told me that ...
Midori ... committed suicide .
She did it in the park .
She killed herself with ...
a bunch of strangers .
They hanged themselves ...
Do you think it was my fault ?
I got so scared that I left the apartment .
I 'm sorry ...
Kobayashi asked his wife to take care of Marika .
I 'm home .
Hi .
Keiko , my wife .
Nice to meet you .
It 's nice of you to let me stay .
" News footage aired the same night "
6 am today in Hironuma Park in Nerima , Tokyo ...
7 men and women were found dead .
They were hanging from the iron bar of the swing .
It 's suspected that the strangers got together to commit suicide .
" 7 bodies hanging from the swing . "
Here are the names of those who hanged themselves .
" February 10 "
Look .
This is the girl who lived upstairs from Marika .
And look at him .
When he first moved in he was just a pleasant , normal guy .
But about half a year ago ... It was around last summer ...
He started to complain a lot to the woman who was living next door .
They argued a lot .
Is that right ?
His neighbor was a tough middle-aged woman .
But eventually she moved out . I guess she felt scared .
The neighbor moved out ?
Do you remember what kind of arguments they used to have ?
He complained about the baby being too noisy .
A baby ?
She didn 't have a baby , though .
It was just her and her boy who was 5 or 6 .
Just a moment , please ...
Is the woman who used to live there ...
Is this the woman ?
Yes , that 's her .
No mistake . It 's her .
" News footage , February 12 "
Next news .
Earlier today at an apartment in Fuchu
a businessman stabbed his wife to death and got arrested .
Our reporter is at the murder site .
Today at 7 : 10 am
a man called the police and said that he 'd stabbed his wife .
The police rushed to the apartment
and found Kimiko Yano stabbed to death .
Also at the site was the suspect , Teruyuki Yano , her husband .
He confessed and was arrested on the spot .
So far he has not told the police why he killed his wife .
Their daughter has been missing for a few months .
Do the police know anything about her disappearance ?
They have no information on her .
Kana , the daughter disappeared on December 19 last year .
No clues have been found .
Today , Marika 's cooking for me .
It 's something yummy .
It 's Spaghetti al Bongole with tomato sauce .
Here , my special pasta and potato salad .
They look great .
And this is ... my special tea .
Isn 't it out of a can ?
No . It 's my special oolong tea .
Would you like some Tabasco ?
Yes ? Here it comes .
A gourmet lunch .
Marika ?
Marika !
Marika , what 's wrong ?
Did I groan ?
Yes .
You seemed to be suffering , you groaned and ...
And some things crashed into the window at the same time .
What is it ?
Are you okay ?
I 'm ...
I 'm the next one to die .
I 'm going to Nagano again .
I 'll talk to Junko Ishii ...
and get her to talk to us .
That will help us solve this mystery .
Hori , the psychic said to watch out for pigeons .
Did he mean that pigeons were a sign of imminent death ?
Let 's visit him tomorrow and ask him about it .
" We visited Mr. Hori "
" to show him the Junko Ishii tape . "
" February 13 "
Mr. Hori .
Are you ready , Mr. Hori ?
This is what we want you to watch .
It 's on this tape .
I 'm sorry .
I 've turned it off .
Mr. Hori .
When you watched the video , did you feel something
or did you see anything ?
Mr. Hori .
Mr. Kobayashi .
Take me to the dam ...
where the village was , the one with the demon rituals .
Why do you want to go there ?
I want to try to perform the ritual myself ...
and see what it does to me .
Absolutely not !
The ritual might have caused Junko Ishii 's possession .
It 's too dangerous .
If the ritual is necessary , I 'll go and do it by myself .
I don 't want to die ...
I have to do it myself .
Please .
Okay then . Let 's go to the dam .
I 'll visit Mr. Hori again
and ask him to come along with us .
Mr. Hori ! We need your help !
What can we do to contain the Kagutaba curse ?
Mr. Hori .
We can 't do this without your help .
Kana ...
The worms have eaten her ...
Maybe these worms are actually Kagutaba .
It 's too quiet around here ...
Where are the dogs now ?
" We drove to the dam where Shimokage village used to be . "
" Shikami Dam "
Are you okay ?
This is where we are on the map .
So the shrine must have been ...
right between that point and the shore .
Off we go .
Let me know when you get back .
Thank you so much .
We 'll be back soon .
Are you okay , Marika ?
You don 't look good . We should go back .
- I 'm okay . - Are you sure ?
We 're almost there .
It 's about here .
Let 's get ready .
Good .
Now , you bow in that special way .
One bow , four claps , one bow ...
How do you feel ?
Talk to me .
I 'm better .
Are you ?
I feel lighter .
Good ! It worked for you .
It was good we came to do this !
It 's gone ...
What 's wrong , Mr. Hori ?
It 's not good ...
What 's not good ?
It 's not good at all ...
I feel so much clearer now .
Thank you so much .
Hurry back !
Oh , no , no , no !
Hurry !
Get out of there !
They 'll eat you up !
Now !
Hurry !
We have to leave the mountain !
Drive away !
Let 's get out of here , then .
Back to the car .
Mr. Hori .
Kana !
Wait a minute , Mr. Hori !
Take care of Marika .
No problem .
Mr. Kobayashi , wait !
Don 't worry , I 'll be right back .
He 's okay . Let 's go .
Are you sure ?
To the car .
Wait a minute !
Are they going to be okay ?
I 'll go look for them later .
How do you feel now ?
Me ? I 'm feeling just fine .
Let 's go then .
Mr. Hori !
Kana !
Mr. Hori , you have to stop !
Wait a minute !
Marika ?
Wait for me , Mr. Hori !
What is it ?
What 's wrong ?
Dogs ?
They 've just been killed ...
Are they the village dogs ?
What 's happening now ?
What 's this ?
It 's a magic field ...
What 's going on here ?
More dead dogs ...
Don 't go in there !
Stay away !
Marika !
Are you okay , Marika ?
Marika , what 's wrong ?
Should I pull over ? Are you okay ?
What 's wrong ? Are you okay ?
Marika !
What 's going on , Mr. Hori ?
What did you find there ?
Marika !
Marika , can you hear me ?
Can you hear me ?
Marika !
It 's a shrine !
Kana ... Kana ...
Mr. Hori !
Mr. Hori , is Kana in there ?
Marika .
Marika !
Kana .
Is she in there ?
This is ancient .
My God !
This pattern is the same as what Kana drew ...
What 's wrong , Mr. Hori ?
Mr. Hori , are you okay ?
Mr. Hori !
Get a grip of yourself !
Marika !
Come back !
Can you hear me ?
Yes ...
Are you okay ?
What is this ?
" We took Marika and Mr. Hori to a local hospital . "
" And we went back to Junko Ishii 's house in search of truth . "
Excuse me !
Let 's go in .
Let 's go and see .
Film here .
Let 's go upstairs .
It 's Junko Ishii .
It 's her . She 's hung herself .
Look at that !
Kagutaba masks .
She 's hung pigeons up here ...
There is a boy behind there !
A boy ?
Behind there !
Kana !
It 's Kana ! It 's her !
She 's cold ...
Are you okay ?
Are you hurt ?
Miyajima .
We have to call the police now .
" Missing girl found dead in Nagano . "
" The boy presumed to be Ishii 's son "
" isn 't actually her child . "
Kobayashi decided to adopt the boy .
" March 6 "
Is it good ?
Yummy ?
It 's a good omelet , isn 't it ?
Do you remember anything about living with that woman ?
Marika , you look very good now .
Yes . I 've been recovering nicely .
All those supernatural things ...
have stopped happening .
Everything 's normal now .
Have you gone back to work ?
Yes . I 'm going back to work soon .
You have to eat it .
Okay , let 's eat everybody .
Let 's eat .
Yummy .
Are you sure ?
Don 't hit me ! Ouch ...
" March 13 "
" Hori has been committed to an institution . "
" No visitors are allowed . "
" March 17 "
I looked around for other things connected to Kagutaba
after you left .
And I found this in my grandfather 's collection .
Here .
It says , " Shimokage 's Way , The Kagutaba method . "
Oh , that 's right .
I guess this scroll depicts
the ritual performed to summon Kagutaba .
These are the monkeys .
And the dogs .
They sacrificed the baby monkeys
and offered them to the medium to eat .
Just like the ancient spell of the Shimokage sorcery ...
which used baby monkeys as sacrifices .
Junko Ishii used Kana Yano as a medium .
She fed Kana the aborted babies ...
in an attempt to resurrect Kagutaba .
It 's only my speculation .
Now that Junko Ishii 's dead
we 'll never know the truth .
I only hope that the Kagutaba curse has been contained .
I guess it 's too late for all of us .
" Camera operator , Hisashi Miyajima "
" Produced by Masafumi Kobayashi "
2 days after " NOROI , The Curse " was completed ...
The Kobayashi house burned down .
Later his wife , Keiko was found dead in the remains .
But Kobayashi wasn 't found . He was declared missing .
3 days after the fire ...
Mitsuo Hori , who had escaped from the institution
was found dead .
" Picture of the Dead Man . "
" Mystery of the man who died in the duct ! "
May 19 , 2004 , a month later
a package was delivered to Sugishobou Publishing .
There was no return address .
The sender 's name was Masafumi Kobayashi .
There was a video camera inside .
And inside the camera ...
a video cassette was intact .
What 's going on , Mr. Hori ?
Are you okay ?
Mr. Hori ?
You ...
You 've been eaten ...
by the worms !
Are you ?
Excuse me ?
Why don 't you put that rock down ?
I can hear Kana ... Her voice comes in my head ...
- In my head ... It says ... - What is it ?
Kagutaba 's alive ...
It lives !
What did you say ?
Kagutaba lives !
But Junko Ishii 's dead now .
Kagutaba has gone now .
You 'd better go back to the institution .
You should go back .
Should I call the police ?
No ... Stop !
What are you doing ?
Stop ! What you 're doing !
Stop it !
There he is !
What do you want ?
It 's him !
He killed Kana ...
Wait , just a minute .
The boy 's a victim , too .
Kana !
Hold on a second !
Calm down .
You have to listen to me .
Just wait a minute .
I 'll help you with whatever you need .
Let go off the boy , okay ?
No !
Stop it !
Are you okay ?
Kana !
Keiko !
Mr. Hori !
Hori ?
Mr. Hori ...
Keiko ?
Keiko !
" Masafumi Kobayashi is still missing today . "